Alexandru Reznic

Mobile Software Engineer(Native Android)

Download Resume in PDF

- Languages:
 - o Romanian native
 - o Russian native
 - o English intermediate
- Contacts:
 - o reznic.a@gmail.com
 - https://t.me/reznic_a
 - https://github.com/a-reznic
 - https://linkedin.com/in/reznic-a
 - stackoverflow.com
 - leetcode.com and source

Moldova, Chisinau. Prefer remote work

Professional experience (18+ years)

Period	Role(Company)	Description
06.2023 - current [1y+]	Senior Android Developer(FullScreenDigital)	Contract, support app, create new apps using Jetpack Compose
01.2023 - 06.2023 [6m]	Senior Android Developer(Happydemy)	Social Media application(like Instagram), Compose, Clean Architecture. google play
11.2021 - 01.2023 [1y3m]	Senior Android Developer(DataDrive)	ELD(Electronic logging device) is a technology used in the trucking industry to track and record a commercial driver's hours of service. Developed from scratch, Kotlin, Clean architecture, MVVM, Koin, Room.

Period	Role(Company)	Description
		Custom theme, support portrait, landscape, phones and tablets.
07.2020 - 11.2021 [1y4m]	Kotlin Backend Developer(Orange)	Orange Money Romania, BFF microservice, Refactoring and Performance of GraphQL microservice. Kotlin, Kafka, Coroutines. Improve requests time from 4s to 2s. Setup TeamCity pipeline.
02.2018 - 07.2020 [2y5m]	Team Lead Android Developer(LogoSoft)	I have led team of 3 people, developed from scratch traft, Single Activity, MVVM, Room, Retrofit, Git Flow, Second app com.vezubr.driver refactoring. Setup Gitlab CI.
10.2014 - 01.2018 [3y2m]	Backend/Frontend Developer(Reznic Software)	App for tourism B2B flintour and Backoffice application for tourism backoffice Spring, Tomcat, Angular 1. Communicated with the client for certain projects to understand the requirements and expectations.
02.2014 - 10.2014 [9m]	Android Developer(Livemile)	Nookbank - Mobile Client Bank app
04.2011 - 02.2014 [3y]	CEO/Team Lead/Android Developer(Reznic Software)	I have led team of 6 people, 4 developers, 1 game designer, 1 graphical designer. Published about 30 games on Google Play. Socket server for Dominoes and Yahtzee games.
04.2010 - 04.2011 [1y]	CEO/Android Developer(Ndroidz Software)	Published about 10 games on Google Play
04.2009 - 04.2010 [1y]	J2ME/Android Developer(MobiTeam/Creafire)	Develop J2ME games, android games
02.2008 - 04.2009 [1y2m]	Java Developer(Vivat Consulting)	J2EE Developer, implemented user interfaces, implemented business logic,

Period	Role(Company)	Description
		performed JUnit tests, changed reports structure, export data to Microsoft Excel file.
06.2006 - 01.2008 [1y7m]	J2ME Developer(Meedia Mobile)	Develop J2ME games, android games

Skills

Programming Languages	Kotlin, Java, Dart, SQL
Frameworks & Libraries	Android, Flutter, Spring Boot, Kafka, GraphQL,Jasper Reports, Junit, Mockito
Databases	PostgreSQL, SQLite
Services	GitLab, GitHub, Docker, Jenkins, GitLab CI, Jira, Youtrack
IDE	Android Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse

Android

- Clean Architecture, MVVM, MVP, MVI, Jetpack Compose
- Room, Realm
- Kotlin Coroutines, RxJava
- Retrofit, OKHTTP, remote logs with Kibana
- Android Jetpack (Navigation, Live Data, View Models)
- Firebase (Crashlytics, Admob, Notification, App Distribution, Analytics, Firestore, Remote Config)
- Self-published apps in Google Play
- Obfuscation Proguard
- CI/CD, Git, Gradle, Unit Testing

Java-Related

- Languages: Java, Kotlin(last 5 years only Kotlin)
- Spring Boot:
 - o Core: DI, Bean Post Processor, Aspect
 - o Web: REST Controller
 - o Security: Basic, Oauth, JWT tokens

- o Data: Entity, Repository, Transaction, Flyway migration
- Kafka
- GraphQL
- Tomcat
- Jasper Reports
- Tests: JUnit, Mockito

Summary

Highly motivated and enthusiastic Senior Mobile Development Engineer with more than 18 years of software engineering experience in the development of entire android apps, games and back-end services. I try to follow development trends and often learn new languages and technologies.

In my free time I play computer games, improve my knowledge in English, listening podcasts.

Projects

reznicsoftware.com

flintour.com

bo.flintour.com

Pet project

compilebenchmark.com

Education

2008 Bachelor of Informatics Ion Creanga University